Let's implement the heap in sea.
Include a studio, and we make that valuable.
Size equal to zero.
We create a new function called swap.
We have learned about it many times in the previous videos and data structures and algorithms, so we
need to swab the value of A to B and the value of B to A.
We create a temporary variable variable called death.
We initialize its value to be B now equal to A and eight equal to them.
Now we create a void, a method called hip ify hip before I met make mean or the arrangement of the
hip in the hip arrangements and orders.
So the smallest number would be the parent and the child would be greater than that.
This is the meaning of hip ify.
It took into that perimeter the entire day we had there in size, and I if size equal, equal to one
then single element in the heap else, if it is greater than one and it contains in the heap, elements
make a largest variable called largest equal to I and and I and added equal to two I.
+1 and input are equal to two I plus two if less than size and array at index L greater than that rate
and next largest, then largest equal to end.
And if are less than size and array at index are greater than a rate at index largest than the largest
equal to.
Please.
Revise the previous video about the heap data structure in order to learn how to hit before and what
is the purpose of it before an operation for a florist does not equal to.
I then swept the elements and then called the heap defy method again, using here that occurred in passing
that say the size and the largest that has that elements.
OK, here we have used the.
The method swab.
And here we have used the hip fire version.
Now we need to make our Floyd Ensor method.
It took him to the perimeter of that ray.
And the new number that we know we need to insert scientists a if size equal equal to zero, then they
put this array element at index zero to new numbers.
So we are inserting it into a new assay.
Otherwise, we need to make a very at index size equal to a new nut.
We are adding it to the list and increase the size by one fourth and I less than or equal to size over
two minus one I less than I greater than zero minus minus.
Then we need to be fine because we need to typify the size over two because we thought we learn about
if we have inserting a new element here, would we need to change that half of the tree before we continue?
OK, so we need to hit before it.
We need to call this method and first the array the size and I pretty.
Now, delayed lead truth, we need to make the lead through a method to into perimeter the array and
and that number that we are going to delete the number from its early start from equal to zero Ireland
than size and I plus plus if no equal equal to array at index I.
So the number it's found, then break.
Otherwise, we swab the arrays and the element of that in the eye with that ray element in the exercise
minus one, and we decrease the size by what otherwise we also need to make the for loop from that the
last the till the middle of the airway.
So this is the other day.
This is the middle.
We start from the end to the middle and we start typifying this three.
Now printing the array, it's very simple.
Function starts from equal to zero eyelids, then sighs, we need to print Ray, and we passed its size,
its corresponding size, and we start printing that as a pretext now to test the code we make and into
Maine, and we start by making an array at that 10.
So we have created arrays with 10 variables, then digits, and now we need to insert into the array
that three called their method insert here called this repository array that we have created and the
value that we are going to insert, which is three and we insert also four, we insert nine, we insert
five and reinsert two.
Now the maximum hip and knee printing array.
We passed the array here and the size for it.
Which is equal to zero.
Now that they lived through it, we delete the array and that a number four, so we need to add two
or delete the four by using that delete root method.
And after that, we didn't need to to print the elements by using the print tray again.
OK.
So this is the heap in a sea.
We have created it correctly and we have used the heap ify method, the insert method and the delete
route method.
So let's go to Java and try to implement the heap.